Yopie Hidayat

WEB DEVELOPER



ABOUT ME

Full Name Yopie Hidayat

Place of birth Situjuh

Date of birth August 31, 1996

CONTACT

Address
Jl. Permai no 32 Rt. 003/015
Tugu Utara, Koja,
North Jakarta

Phone 0813 8723 2847

Email yopiehidayat12@gmail.com

SKILL

- ☐ Strong in PHP Programming
- ☐ Codelgniter, Laravel,
 Native PHP
- ☐ HTML, CSS, Ajax, Jquery
- ☐ Rest Web Service APIs Codelgniter/Laravel
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server Database
- Experienced using GIT
- ☐ Experienced using other programming language like Java, Kotlin, Flutter
- Experienced using Android Studio

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an Experienced Web Developer especially using PHP Programming. I have been working in IT Development since 2016. I have strong skills in PHP Programming and have developed many project websites using PHP programming, especially using the Codelgniter/Laravel framework. In addition, I also like to make mobile apps. I am interested in joining a growing company where I can use my skills and experience to achieve company goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer (Web Developer)

2016 - 2018

I have worked as an IT freelancer since 2016 and have been involved in many project web applications. In general, the project was built using PHP programming, especially using Codelgniter/Laravel framework. My responsibilities for: design overall architecture of the web application, design user interface, design database system, develop the required features, manage backend and work on bug fixing and improving application performance.

PT. Perkebunan Nusantara V (PHP Developer)

March 2018 - July 2018

Here I have the opportunity to do an internship and be placed in the Information Technology section. I worked as PHP Developer and have responsibilities for: design overall architecture of the web application, developing and maintaining internal systems, handling bug fixing and maintaining quality and ensuring responsiveness of applications.

PT. Lawencon Internasional (PHP Developer)

December 2018 - December 2019

I worked onsite on IT Research and Development in PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia (BRI) as PHP Developer. My responsibilities are: developing and maintaining internal web applications, handling bug fixing from internal testers, creating REST Web Services APIs, working with outside data sources and APIs, and designing database of the web application.

■ **MeetAp** (Trainer Web and Mobile Dev)

March 2019 - Present

Here I was appointed as a web trainer especially in PHP programming. My responsibilities are: teach basic PHP Programming, create RESTful APIs with PHP Programming, teach database design based on a developed system, research new technology for application improvement and help handle bug fixing from participants.

PT. Barumi Multi Talenta (Web Developer)

January 2020 - May 2020

I worked onsite on Business Technology in PT. Cipta Krida Bahari as PHP Developer. My responsibilities are: developing and maintaining internal web application Human Resource Information System (HRIS), handling bug fixing from internal testers, creating REST Web Services APIs, working with outside data sources and APIs, and designing database of the web application.

PT. Waruna Nusa Sentana (Application Programmer)

June 2021 - Present

I'm currently working at PT. Waruna Nusa Sentana as Application Programmer. My responsibilities are: developing and maintaining internal web & application company, backup server check, handling bug fixing from internal testers, creating REST Web Services APIs, working with outside data sources and APIs, and designing database of the web application.

FORMAL EDUCATION

- Elementary School (2002 2008) : SDN 3 Situjuah Banda Dalam
- Junior High School (2008 2011): SMPN 1 Situjuah
- Senior High School (2011 2014): SMAN 1 Kota Payakumbuh
- Bachelor Degree (2014 2018): Informatics Engineering, Politeknik Caltex